Guide to the Women Writing Women's Lives Records TAM.316
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Women Writing Women's Lives Records
1989-2023
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Women Writing Women's Lives
Chamberlain, Kathy
Chase, Norah C.
Munker, Dona
Stern, Claire
TAM.316
8 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 cassette box, 2 CD boxes, and 1 card box
3 audiocassettes
4 VHS
16 CDs
7.7 Gigabytes in 47 computer files
Women Writing Women's Lives is a seminar of women authors, poets, academics, and journalists engaged in writing biographies and memoirs. The Women Writing Women's Lives Records (1989-2023) consists of administrative files, subject files, notes and lectures from the group's monthly meetings, and oral history interviews of group members.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Women Writing Women's Lives donated a collection of their records in 2004. In 2008, a donation of 57 photographs was made by Claire Morris Stern, chair of the WWWL Archives Committee. An additional donation was made by Norah Chase in 2010. In 2013 Claire Morris Stern sent a donation of her personal files, which were added to this collection. An additional three boxes of WWWL's records from 2002-2015 were donated in 2015. In 2019 an accretion of administrative and seminar documents from 2017-2018 were donated by Julia Van Haaften. Van Haaften donated a similar accretion of more recent administrative records in June 2025. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2004.001, 2004.007, 2004.008, NPA.2008.045, NPA.2009.027, 2013.044, 2015.038, 2017.073, 2019.035, and 2025.059.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into four series:
Series I: Administrative and Committee Records, arranged alphabetically
Series II: Claire Morris Stern Records, arranged in the order of provenance
Series III: Session Records, arranged chronologically; and
Series IV: Oral History Interviews, arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name.
Historical Note
Founded in 1990, Women Writing Women's Lives (WWWL) is an ongoing seminar of about sixty women engaged in writing book-length biographies and memoirs. Its members include academics, poets, journalists and novelists. WWWL is affiliated with the Center for the Study of Women and Society and the Center for the Humanities at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York. Monthly meetings, planned by a Steering Committee, are arranged in order for members to present work for discussion, share ideas, and hear about the work of outside presenters.
Scope and Contents
The Women Writing Women's Lives Records (1989-2023) contain the materials of Women Writing Women's Lives (WWWL) and its members. The collection is primarily comprised of proceedings from monthly meetings, but also includes materials such as membership questionnaires, correspondence, photographs of members and meetings, and subject files. The collection also contains correspondence, ephemera, images, and video recordings from Women Writing Women's Lives events including anniversary celebrations and speaking events.
The collection also contians the administrative files of Claire Morris Stern, who was a founding member of the organization and served as the chair of the Archive Committee. Her files contain correspondence, photographs, and materials related to special events including the Women Writing Women's Lives 20th Anniversary celebration.
Oral history interviews recorded on audiocassettes and audio CDs are held in this collection, along with paper transcripts and biographical notes. Electronic Records include digital audio files of each interview. These interviews were conducted by other WWWL members and Tamiment director Michael Nash between 2006 and 2009. They discuss topics such as the founding of the writing seminar, and the ways in which participation in WWWL shaped these authors' careers as biographers.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Separated Materials
Materials related to the donation of Women Writing Women's Lives Records to Tamiment have been removed from the collection.
Appraisal
Prior to processing in 2025, several duplicate oral history transcripts were removed from this collection and returned to donors.
Women -- Biography.; Correspondence.; Women biographers.; New York (N.Y.).; Lecture notes.; Minutes (administrative records); Women historians; Historians; Oral histories (literary works); Alexander, Meena, 1951-; Bair, Deirdre; Bernikow, Louise, 1940-; Bingham, Sallie; Brownstein, Rachel M.; Chamberlain, Kathy; Chase, Norah C.; Chevigny, Bell Gale; City University of New York. Center for the Study of Women and Society; City University of New York. Graduate School and University Center; Cook, Blanche Wiesen; DeSalvo, Louise A., 1942-; Duggan, Lisa, 1954-; Gray, Francine du Plessix; Hertog, Susan; Mann, Emily; Mathews, Nancy Mowll; Moore, Honor, 1945-; Munker, Dona; Painter, Nell Irvin; Prioleau, Elizabeth Stevens, 1942-; Stern, Claire; Shapiro, Susan
- Series I: Administrative and Committee Files, 1989-2023
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I: Administrative and Committee Files (1989-2023) consist of administrative records such as membership applications and questionnaires, financial records, and minutes of the Steering Committee meetings. Clipping and subject files on topics related to women's biography and biographers and photographs of members at a 2008 meeting (where Salli Bingham was the guest speaker) are also included.
  - Anniversary Programs - 5th Anniversary Symposium, Mar 17, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary Programs - 10th Anniversary Conference, Dec 8, 2000; cuid44411
    - Correspondence and ephemera (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Event recording -- Tape 1, cuid44412 (Box Shared Tamiment 201, Vhs cuid44412)
    - Event recording -- Tape 2, cuid44413 (Box Shared Tamiment 201, Vhs cuid44413)
    - Event recording -- Tape 3, cuid44414 (Box Shared Tamiment 201, Vhs cuid44414)
    - Event recording -- Tape 4, cuid44415 (Box Shared Tamiment 201, Vhs cuid44415)
  - Anniversary Programs - 15th Anniversary Celebration, Oct 28, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary Programs - 20th Anniversary Program - Tamiment, May 3, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary Program -- 25th Anniversary Conference, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 1, Box 8)
  - Anniversary Programs -- 30th Anniversary Conference, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Annual Survey Results (Samples), 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Archives Committee, 2003-2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Articles (mostly on Women and Biography), 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Attendance Lists, undated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Attendance Lists and Seating Charts, 2002-2011 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Attendance Lists, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bernhardt, Debra: Memorial, May 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bernikow, Louise, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Book Covers of Publications by Members, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Brochure - Old and New Versions, 2002-2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Conference, 10th Anniversary, Dec 8, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Contact Lists, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Contact Lists, 1997-2013 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cook, Blanche Wiesen, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2011 (Box 4, Folder 10-19)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2014 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Cover Letter and Questionnaire Drafts for Mailing, Aug 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dona Munker New Chair Women Writing Women's Lives (CD containing 48 images and 2 videos), Fall 2011 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Finances, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Floppy Discs (administrative files), 1996, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Flyers, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Grant Proposal (New York Council for the Humanities), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gail Hornstein Speaking to the Women Writing Women's Lives Seminar on the subject of Agnes's Jacket (CD containing 1hr 50 minute audio recording), May 4, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - History and Origins (misc. notes on co-founders) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Issues/Controversies, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Issues: "France", 2006 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Issues: "Ideologically Skewed", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Issues: "Intimidated", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Issues: "Plagiarism (as it affected B. Wineapple and Carolyn Burke)", 2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jane Cumberbatch - Joseph F. Murphy Institute Liaison to WWWL, 2002-2015 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mary Ann Caws on CUNY GC President Frances Horowitz's "Woman to Woman" (VHS), Dec 8, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Member Obituaries, 2017-2018 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Membership Applications (not comprehensive), 1996-2011 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Membership Applications: A-J, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membership Applications: K-M, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership Applications: N-Z, 1993-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Membership Directory, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Membership: General, 1992-2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Membership: General, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Membership Lists, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Memoir Course (never materialized), 2007 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Menus, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mission Statement, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Mission Statement, Guidelines, Group Archives, 1995-2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - News Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Notes: General, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Obituary/Memorial Material, 2001-2003, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Outreach Committee, 2004-2007 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photographs from Meeting, May 5, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Photographs of Members, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Photographs of members, 2005-04-05 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Policies and Procedures, 2011-2014 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Recording of Meeting (on CD), May 4, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Restaurants, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Sample Form Letters, 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Sign-in Sheets, 2017-2019 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Special Events, 2011-2014 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Special Reports, 2011-2014 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Steering Committee Business, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Steering Committee Business, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Steering Committee Business, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32A)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 34, Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2010-2011 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2012-2013 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2013-2014 (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2014-2015 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2015-2016 (Box 8, Folder 14, Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2016-2017 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2017-2018 (Box 7, Folder 4, Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2018-2019 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2019-2020 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2020-2021 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2021-2022 (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
  - Steering Committee Documents, 2022-2023 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Steering Committee Meetings, 2006-2014 (Box 6, Folder 28-70)
  - Steering Committee Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Sue Shapiro -- Notes and Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Summer Survey, 2011-2014 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Tamiment Women's Lives (2 CDs containing 1hour 24 minute recording), May 3, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Topics, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Women Writing Women's Lives Event Photographs, 2004-2007 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Writings on Biography: General, 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series II: Claire Morris Stern Records, 1990-2010; 2013.044; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in the order of provenance.
  Series II: Claire Morris Stern Records (1990-2010) contains the administrative files of Claire Morris Stern, who was a founding member of the organization and served as the chair of the Archive Committee. Her files contain correspondence, photographs, and materials related to special events including the Women Writing Women's Lives 20th Anniversary celebration.
  - Redstockings, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Early Organizational Records: Materials Inventory, 1992-2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Early Records, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Photographs, May 3, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 20th Anniversary Meeting Materials, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Women Writing Women's Lives Brochures, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Member Publications, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bingham Correspondence, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 20th Anniversary Celebration, May 3, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 10th and 20th Anniversary Materials, 2000, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re: Meetings and Speakers, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re: Interviews with Founders, 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
- Series III: Session Records, 1991-2009
  This series is arranged chronologically with records grouped together by content.
  Series III: Session Records (1991-2009) contains announcements, attendance sheets, lectures and notes from the organization's monthly meetings. Names of lecturers are indicated in the folder title.
  - List of Sessions by Year, 2002-2011 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Session Records (Eunice Lipton), Oct 14, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Session Records (Liz Wood), Nov 11, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo and Sue A. Shapiro), Dec 9, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Session Records (Anne Higonnet and Nancy Mowll Mathews), Feb 10, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Session Records (Blanche Wiesen Cook), Mar 8, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Session Records (Sallie Bingham, Ellen Chessler, Nancy Rubin), Apr 13, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Session Records (Shereen Brysac, Lisa Duggan, and Francine du Plessix Gray), May 11, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Session Records (Ellen Chessler and Gloria Ehrlich), Oct 5, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Session Records (Bell Chevigny), Nov 9, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Session Records (Norah Chase and Nell Painter), Dec 14, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Blanche Wiesen Cook, Francine du Plessix Gray and Aileen Ward), Jan 11, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Session Records (Christie McDonald and Nancy Pittman), Feb 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Carole Klein, and Louise DeSalvo), Mar 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Session Records (Sharen O'Brien, and Joan Weimer), Apr 12, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Session Records (Gail Hornstein), May 10, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Session Records (Sallie Bingham, Dorothy Helly, and Nell Painter), Oct 4, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Session Records (Joan Hendrick and Martha Saxton), Nov 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Grace Hechinger), Dec 13, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Brooke Kroegar), Jan 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Session Records (Deborah Baker and Thadious Davis), Feb 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Session Records (Harriet Hyman Alonso and Betty Caroli), Mar 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Session Records (Barbara Lachman and Nancy Rubin), Apr 11, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Blanche Wiesen Cook, and Louise DeSalvo), May 9, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Session Records (Carole Klein and Joan Mellon), Oct 3, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Session Records (Harriet Hyman Alonso, Patricia Bosworth), Nov 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Session Records (Nell Painter and Brenda Silver), Dec 5, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo and Carol Stanger), Feb 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Session Records (Beth Diefendorf and Glenn Shafer), Mar 13, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Session Records (Meena Alexander and Paula Giddings), Apr 10, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Session Records (Kathleen Brady and Honor Moore), May 8, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Session Records (Jill Johnston and Suzannah Lessard), Oct 2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Session Records (Blanche Wiesen Cook), Nov 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Session Records (Emily Mann), Dec 11, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Session Records (Honor Moore), Feb 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Session Records (Joan Acocella and Susan Hallgarth), Mar 11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Session Records (Liz Harlan), Apr 6, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo), May 13, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Session Records, Oct 7, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Session Records (Christina Baker and Christina Baker Kline), Dec 2, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Session Records (Multiple Sessions), 1997-2015 (Box 3, Folder 2-20)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi and Bell Chevigny), Jan 13, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Session Records (Susan Hertog and Stacy Schiff), Feb 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Linda Reed), Mar 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Session Records (Margaret Gibson and Stephanie Strickland), Apr 14, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Session Records (Betty Boyd Caroli and Nancy Rubin), May 5, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Session Records (Norah Chase and Alix Kates Shulman), Oct 6, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Session Records (Ed McCoyd and Lisa Paddock), Nov 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Session Records (Claire Coss and Judith Sloan), Dec 8, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Session Records (Louise Bernikow and Jane Marcus), Jan 5, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Session Records (Bell Chevigny and Noel Riley Fitch), Feb 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Session Records (Gail Levin and Patricia Valenti), Mar 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Brenda Wineapple), Apr 6, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Session Records (Dorothy Kaufman and Pat Laurence), May 4, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Session Records, Oct 5, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Session Records (Dorothy O. Helly and Polly Howells), Nov 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Session Records (Shareen Brysac, Blanche Weisen Cook, Dona Munker, and Ellen Schrecker), Dec 7, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Session Records (Patty O'Toole), Jan 11, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Session Records (Sydney Ladensohn Stern and Judith Hennessee), Feb 8, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Session Records (Betty Caroli and Carol Stanger), Mar 8, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi, Blanche Weisen Cook, and Ellen Schrecker), Apr 12, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Session Records (Kathy Chamberlain and Cheryl Torsney), May 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Session Records (Barbara Horn), Oct 4, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Session Records (Alexandra Johnson and Molly Vaux), Nov 1, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Session Records (Lois Beachy Underhill), Dec 6, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Carol Stanger), Jan 10, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Session Records (Joyce Seltzer and Jane von Mehren), Feb 7, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Session Records (Harriet Alonso and Barbara McManus), Mar 6, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Session Records (Carole Klein and Marion Meade), Apr 3, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Session Records (Carolyn Heilbrun), May 1, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Session Records (Constance Rosenblum and Eve Golden), Oct 2, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Session Records (Susan Brownmiller and Donez Xiques), Nov 6, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Session Records (Christine Stansell), Dec 4, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Session Records (Deborah Gorham and Joanne Grant), Jan 7, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Session Records (Aileen Christianson), Feb 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Session Records (Rachel Brownstein and Dana Heller), Mar 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Session Records (Anne M. Wyatt-Brown), May 7, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Session Records (Adrienne Block and Rachel Brownstein), Oct 1, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Session Records (Joyce C. Harte and Wendy Orange), Nov 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi and Sherry Gorelick), Dec 3, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Session Records (Betsy Prioleau and Nancy Schoenberger), Jan 7, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Session Records (Meena Alexander and Flavia Alaya), Feb 4, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Session Records (Gail Hornstein), Mar 4, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Session Records (Dona Munker), Apr 8, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Carla Peterson), May 13, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Session Records (Jill Norgren), May 5, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Session Records (Michael Nash), Dec 1, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Session Records (Victoria Olsen), Feb 2, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Session Records (Jennifer Fleishner and Diane Jacobs), Mar 1, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Session Photographs, 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Session Records (Attendance Sheets), 2011-2014 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Seminar Session and Events Documents, 2017-2018 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Biographical Fiction/Fictional Biography", Jan 10, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Place", Nov 5, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Memoir and Biography" Alix Schulman and Brenda Wineapple, Apr 7, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Fathers", May 2, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Imperialist Women", Apr 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Redheads", Sep 25, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Writing about Men", Oct 1, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Organizing Session Samples - "Chapter by Chapter - Finding a Form", Nov 2, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Series IV: Oral History Interviews, 2006-2009; 2 Linear Feet in one manuscript box, one cassette box, and two CD boxes; 3 audiocassettes; 4 VHS; 16 CDs; 7.7 Gigabytes in 47 computer files
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name.